Md Sazid Uddin

🤳 +8801733738489 👿 initialsaremsu@gmail.com 🛗 linkedin/sazid-uddin 🕥 github/manchitro 🗣 Dhaka, Bangladesh

Introduction

I am a dedicated software engineer with nearly 2 years of professional experience, holding a bachelor's degree in software engineering. My passion lies in the realm of artificial intelligence and neural networks, and I have actively engaged in research, particularly in the field of disease recognition using deep learning techniques. As a fast learner and avid problem solver, I aspire to further my academic journey by pursuing a master's or Ph.D. degree in computer science with a specific focus on artificial intelligence. My goal is to work on intelligent systems that can tackle realworld challenges, and I am eager to contribute to cutting-edge research under the mentorship of experienced experts in the field.

Education

American International University-Bangladesh

Jan. 2023 - Present

Master of Science in Computer Science

Dhaka, Banqladesh

- Specialization in Intelligent Systems
- CGPA 3.80 out of 4.00 (Ongoing)

American International University-Bangladesh

Jan. 2018 - Oct. 2021

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering

Dhaka, Banqladesh

• CGPA 3.84 out of 4.00

Relevant Coursework

- Machine Learning & Neural Networks
- Natural Language Processing
- Computer Vision & Pattern Recognition
- Human Computer Interaction
- Design and Analysis of Algorithms

- Data Structures
- Compiler Design
- Linear Algebra & Fourier Analysis
- Discrete Mathematics

Experience

Orion Informatics Ltd

Jan 2022 - Present

Junior Software Engineer

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Managing large scale web applications for Equiniti (formerly AST Financial)
- Maintaining and extending front-end and back-end services using SpringBoot, Angular and MS SQL Server
- Built high-performance data pipelines using Apache Kafka and Kafka Streams

Orion Informatics Ltd

Jul 2021 - Dec 2021

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Software Engineering Intern

Oct 2020 - Dec 2020

American International University-Bangladesh

Teaching Assistant

- Advised students on various topics of Compiler Design
- Help conduct and prepare materials for lectures

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Research Projects

Mammogram ROI Classification Using Reinforcement Learning | PyTorch

Spring 2023

• A multi-agent reinforcement learning model where multiple agents observe parts of image and communicate with each other and give consensus for breast cancer classification using regions of interest in mammogram images.

Deep Learning Model for Multi-Organ Cancer Classification | Keras, TensorFlow

Summer 2023

• Developed a hybrid model capable of classifying cervical cancer and acute lymphoma from images. Feature extraction using MobileNet and DenseNet; feature classification using SVM.

Generating Synthetic Breast Cancer ROI Images Using GAN | PyTorch

Summer 2023

• Developed a Generative Adversarial Network (GAN) for generating synthetic breast cancer ROI images to augment and enhance sparsely available datasets.

Technical Skills

Deep Learning: PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras Web Development: SpringBoot, Angular

Languages: Python, Java, JavaScript, SQL, LATEX

Developer Tools: VS Code, Intellij Idea **Technologies/Frameworks**: Linux, GitHub

Standardized Tests

GRE IELTS

Analytical Writing: 5.0/6.0 - 91st Percentile

Verbal Reasoning : 154/170 - 62nd Percentile Listening - 8.5/9.0 Writing - 6.5/9.0 Quantitative Reasoning : 156/170 - 54th Percentile Reading - 7.5/9.0 Speaking - 7.5/9.0

References

Dr. M. Firoz Mridha Associate Professor of CS

American International University-Bangladesh

Email: firoz.mridha@aiub.edu

Website: AIUB

Research Profile: ResearchGate

Shafqat Ahmed

Overall - 7.5/9.0

Chief Technology Officer

Orion Informatics Ltd.

Email: shafqat.ahmed@orion-informatics.com

Website: LinkedIn